Guide to the James D. and Eleanor F. Newton Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
James D. and Eleanor F. Newton papers
1872-2000
MS 1592
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
27.75
(27 boxes)
The papers consist of correspondence, audiotape transcripts, subject files, writings, and printed material relating to Thomas Edison, Henry Ford, Harvey Firestone, Alexis Carrel, and Charles and Anne Morrow Lindbergh, and used for the book Uncommon friends: Life with Thomas Edison, Henry Ford, Harvey Firestone, Alexis Carrel & Charles Lindbergh, by James D. Newton. Also included are correspondence, subject files, and writings relating to Eleanor Forde Newton.
Newton, James D. (James Draper), 1905-1999
Biographical / Historical
James Draper Newton (born in Philadelphia, 1905-1999) and his wife Eleanor Napier Forde Newton (born in Montreal, Canada, 1899-2003) were close friends of Anne Morrow and Charles A. Lindbergh. At the age of twenty, Newton became a real estate developer in Fort Myers, Florida, and became well acquainted with Thomas Edison, Henry Ford, and Harvey Firestone. In 1928 he was hired by Firestone and served in various administrative positions. In the 1930s Newton became increasingly involved in the Oxford Movement, later named Moral Re-Armament (MRA), and left Firestone in 1936 to work for the movement. Eleanor Forde was a long-time teacher and leader in the movement. Newton guided the Lindberghs on boat trips through the Everglades and the Florida Keys and inspired their dedication to conserving the Florida environment. Charles Lindbergh served as best man at the wedding of James and Eleanor in 1943. In 1967, the Newtons "retired" from full-time work for MRA and established a highly successful real estate development business in Fort Myers Beach. James Newton's book, Uncommon friends: life with Thomas Edison, Henry Ford, Harvey Firestone, Alexis Carrel & Charles Lindbergh, with a foreword by Anne Morrow Lindbergh, was published in 1987. A documentary based on the book, narrated by Walter Cronkite, was first broadcast on public television in 1999. The Newtons received many awards for their contributions to community improvement projects including the restoration of the Edison and Ford estate museums. Their home on an unspoiled beachfront is now Newton Park in Fort Myers Beach.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Arrangement
Material is arranged by name of person.
Scope and Contents
The papers consist of correspondence, audiotape transcripts, subject files, writings, and printed material relating to Thomas Edison, Henry Ford, Harvey Firestone, Alexis Carrel, and Charles and Anne Morrow Lindbergh, and used for the book Uncommon Friends: Life with Thomas Edison, Henry Ford, Harvey Firestone, Alexis Carrel & Charles Lindbergh, by James D. Newton. Also included are correspondence, subject files, and writings relating to Eleanor Forde Newton.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of James D. and Eleanor F. Newton, 1989, 1993, and 1997; gift of Eleanor Newton, 2000; gift of Willard Hunter, 2004.
Carrel, Alexis, 1873-1944; Edison, Thomas A. (Thomas Alva), 1847-1931; Firestone, Harvey Samuel, 1868-1938; Ford, Henry, II, 1917-1987; Forde, Eleanor Napier; Lindbergh, Charles A. (Charles Augustus), 1902-1974; Newton, James D. (James Draper), 1905-1999
- Inventory, Circa 1930-1990
  - "Uncommon Friends": List of transcripts/tapes
    - Anne Morrow Lindbergh Interview w/ Eric Severeid, 5/27/77 (Side B) (Box 1)
    - JDN w/Hunter at Beach, 10/18/80 (Sides 1 and 2) (Box 1)
    - JDN w/ Wm. Spear Trans. 9/29/80 (Side 1) (Box 1)
      Scope and Contents
      First meeting Mrs. Edison/Opening Edison Park/Edison with flu/Mr. Ford notes of jokes/"Friendship Walk"/Firestone & Ford meeting/"Captain on the Bridge".
    - JDN w/ Hunter 10/4/80 (Sides A and B) (Box 1)
      Edison - Chewing tobacco & cigars/Teeth pulled/DOC/Death of Edison/Voting machine/Firestone & Ford meeting/Firestone days/Radio program - Harvey Jr.
    - JDN & Dick Dennis Early July 1981 (Sides 1 & 2) (Box 1)
      First discussion of the book outline/Meeting Mrs. Edison/Statue/Edison park/Carrel "Culture of Organs"/Lindbergh July 15 Conv. Centennary of Carrel/Cardinal Hayes Ray Fredette/Chronology of associations.
    - Book comments Highland N-C. 6/21/80 (Side 1) (Box 1)
    - Book May 18, 1981 (Sides 1 & 2) (Box 1)
      There was great humor/Hawaii w/ Ellie/Charles arriving Hawaii from hospital/Death of Charles/The turkey hunter/Tobacco man/Letter of woman (secret alcoholic).
    - Randoms on beach, Hunter 11/1/80 (Sides 1 & 2) (Box 1)
      Oxford group/Bud Firestone/Mrs. Newton funderal.
    - Carrel/Hunter transl. 10/17/80; Father Gaudet's translation/St. Gildas/Carrel (Box 1)
    - George West/Fr. Gaudet Re: Carrel (Sides 1 & 2) (Box 1)
    - JDN—praying in the army; Toytown tavern (Vince Anderson 6/81) (Side 1) (Box 1)
    - JDN/Hunter, 8/9/81 (Sides 1 & 2) (Box 1)
      Childhood/Western/"I was born Mar. 30th"/Sales career/String of pearls/Brake-Lining experiment/Integrity/Direct way/Edison/Ford & jokes/Humor/Madison Square Garden/Will Rogers/Intuitiveness/Sure footedness/ Faith/Lindbergh/Solitude/Core of one's existence/Charles chose New Testament to take to Pacific/Six men commonalities.
    - JDN—long letter to Bill J. 2/28/81 (Sides 1 & 2 ) (Box 1)
      "Sitting under a Chickee"/Bud Firestone/Train journey with Firestone/Ways, GA./Edison park/Ford $5.00 day/Edison birthday parties/Dinners with Carrel Century club/"Man the unknown"/experiments with Mdme. Carrel/ESP—Haitian story Boat coming in/Illiac & St. Gildas/Lindberghs in Fla./Carrel centennary—Charles' appearance there/Edison..invented the 20th Century/Firestone & Ford meeting/MRA..strikes/India/etc.
    - Santini & JDN-Edison WWI/Hurricanes 1920's "Guy" Edison (TWH listed 10/80) (Box 1)
    - Recap of conv. JDN w/ TWH 10/16/80 (Box 1)
    - JDN w/ TWH Oct. 18 1980 (Ft.Myers Beach) (Sides 1 & 2) (Box 1)
      Edison—"I remember Thomas Edison"/"The man who invented the 20th century"/Mrs. Edison's description/Edison park/Statue/Birthday press conference/etc.
    - Query letters WTH/October, 1980 (Side 1) (Box 1)
      General game plan/Lindbergh/Newton/Edison.
    - JDN speech on Mr. Ford. Roof Top Dinner, October, 1977 (Side 1) (Box 1)
    - Edison home tour. Trans, October 1980 (Sides 1& 2) (Box 1)
    - JDN w/Dick Dennis 8/21/81 (Sides 1A & 1B & 1) (Box 1)
      Charles—"I'll go anywhere with you"/ Meeting Charles/Dinner in French restaurant/Carrel—Telling story of Toytown tavern/No college education/Simplicity/"Quality of Life"/"Balance"/ Experience at Stockbridge-Mountain Ranges/Carrel/"It's as real as that table…"/Mdme Carrel/Clairvoyance/Lindbergh—Talking on a rock beside his house… in France/Lindbergh talking about wanting to fly.. the Jenny.. when the Lindberghs came to Fla.…
    - JDN—Vince et al. 5/21/81 (Sides 1 & 2) (Box 1)
      Martha's Vineyard w/ Lindbergh/Swimming in winter/Visiting Ford w/ Lindbergh, World War II German medal/MA Newton, beach hotel/Pier story/Western days/Travelling up north for Belber/Florida real estate/Early days/Working for Firestone/Story of the gangsters/Young days/Cement mixer fall.
    - JDN w/TWH "I remember Henry Ford." 10/14/80 (Sides 1 & 2) Transc. 11/12/80 (Box 1)
      Carrel/Burying silver/ Willow run/Lindbergh/Fairlanes w/Fords/Sorenson/Bennet.
    - JDN w/ Lisa - news - press 5/2/81 (Sides A & B) (Box 1)
      Lindbergh trip to Russia/Mdme Carrel's experiment to find him/Firestone days/Depression/Sears ad/Ford 6 month shutdown V8 engine/Brake-lining story/Changing fenders/Making decisions/Direct approach, simplicty/Charles illness/Edison statue/Early real estate days/Florida/DOC coming down for vacation with Ma/Visit to Arctic/Hurricanes.
    - JDN w/ Dick Dennis late Aug./Early Sept. 81 (Side 1) (Box 1)
      ESP/Haiti/Charles seeing backs of statues/Perfectly formed where no one could see/Visiting St. Gilda's with Ellie/Carrel's grave.
    - JDN w/ TWH Trans. 10/8/80 (Sides 1 & 2) (Box 1)
      Lindbergh/"The thing from Reeve" at fund meeting/How Lindbergh wrote/Lindbergh's journey to Maui/Story of being forced down/Farmhouse/"Well, we've only got one chicken left"/ Anne Lindbergh/"Where are you going to store the luncheon boxes…"/Charles' reaction to press.
    - Charles death in Maui/Simplicity (Sides 1 & 2) (Box 1)
      Simplicity/Sleeping in Malanin's office/Quality of life/Carrel/Philosophy.
    - Ellie interviewing JDN May 3 (Ft. Lauderdale) (Sides & 2) (Box 1)
      Early Days, selling wallpaper, etc./Falling in the cement hole/Bil1 Freeman/Living at 63rd & Lansdale/Boyhood pranks/DOC's work/Watching him/Diagnostician/Edison extracting teeth.
    - Mr. Edison being against cigarettes (Sides 1 & 2) (Box 1)
      Mr. Edison being against cigarettes/Hoover story/Early days in basement/ Transmitter set/Talking to Robert/Deciding to go off hoboing w/ Ralph/Doc's letter "to whom it may concern.."/Bovine, Texas/Cowboy Days, Tombstone, Arizona
    - TV program (Sides 2, 1) (Box 1)
      Death of Lindbergh/First meeting w/ Lindbergh/ French restaurant/Rifle range in living room/Lindbergh practical jokes.
    - Simplicity (Sides 1 & 2) (Box 1)
      Simplicity/Back of simplicity/Integrity/Edison w/ boys from MIT/Brake-lining story/Firestone/Quotes from T. de C. CAL—arrival in Paris.
    - Edison (Sides 1 & 2) (Box 1)
      Edison/CAL Toytown tavern early days/Marcel Wagner/Firestone/"I remember when he took a glass of milk"/Sales trips to North for Belber Quotes from Kimana/Sakorsky/Wearing Edison's silk nightgown.
    - C.A.L. The last 8 days From New York Hospital to Mauii and Death and Burial and recollections of Land Lindbergh Recorded by Land (Box 1)
      Page 1-12 transcript; Side 1 is Conversation Land & Susie recall trip to Africa/Philippines by CAL.
    - C.A.L. The last 8 days From New York Hospital to Mauii and Death and Burial and recollections of land Lindbergh Recorded by Land (Box 1)
      General
      Page 13-32 transcript.
    - C.A.L. The last 8 days From New York Hospital to Mauii and Death and Burial and recollections of land Lindbergh Recorded by Land (Box 1)
      Page 33-52 transcript.
    - C.A.L. The last 8 days From New York Hospital to Maui and Death and Burial and recollections of land Lindbergh Recorded by Land (Box 1)
      Page 53-70 transcript.
    - JDN & Bill Spear recorded at Edison College for Edison Home Board, 7/24/81 (Side 1) (Box 1)
      "Birthday parties"/Story of Alan Hoover smoking/ Invention of voting machine/Doc's treatment of Edison/Extraction of teeth/Mention of Mr. Ford & Mr. Firestone very briefly.
    - CAL—story of the pancakes/Boat trips shark river/Tortugas/ Children of CAL & AML/CAL'S consideration of others/CAL & America first/War years JDN/JDN'S experience in hospital/Molasses on the mast story/ "One more stroke" swimming story (Box 1)
    - TWH interviews Harry Hasegawa RE: Charles Lindbergh Dec. 1980 and Henry Kahula in Maui Jan. 1981 (Sides 1, 2) (Box 1)
    - TWH interviews John Hanchett and Mrs. Milton Howell Jan. 1981 in Maui Re: Charles Lindbergh (Sides 1 & 2) (Box 1)
    - TWH interviews Ed & Jeannie Pechin and Samuel Pryor in Maui Dec. 1980 Re: Charles Lindbergh (Sides 1, 2) (Box 1)
    - TWH interviews JDN & Sam Pryor at Wananalua Church, HANA Dec. 1980 Re: "Faith of the Lone Eagle" (Side 1) (Box 1)
    - JDN w/ BABS (Sides 1, 2) (Box 1)
      Discusses CAL & America first, the Carrels and experiments with ESP/St. Gilda's visit of JDN.
    - JDN recollections of hunting with Bill Moger/JDN Christmas breakfast 1981 speech (Sides 1A, 2B) (Box 1)
    - T. Willard Hunter at Claremont UCC Congreg. Church talks of the "Faith of Charles Lindbergh" (3/30/80) (Box 1)
      Side, Side 2-Will Rogers.
    - JDN talks with the Hallwards 1/21/82 at. FMB (Sides 1 & 2) (Box 1)
      RE: JDN talks of Willow Run/ Ford/Firestone Days/CAL at Ford Plant/CAL transatlantic flight 1927/Poland invaded/War years/America first/Carrel's ESP experiments on St. Gilda's/ Train ride in France in P.J.'s/Edison coming to Ft. Myers.
    - CAL, hospital—last visit/JDN (Sides 1 & 2) (Box 1)
      Hospital in South Pacific/Visit to Trappist Monastery/JDN Florida early days/Dom Alexis/Father Gaudet(With Hallwards 1/24 & 1/25/82).
    - JDN w/ Hallwards 1/25 & 1/26/82 (Sides 1 & 2) (Box 1)
      Early real estate days in FLA./Early Firestone days/Learning to sail/Baron Collier/M.R.A./Meeting Ed Moore, and then Carrel, and then Lindbergh.
    - JDN w/ the Hallwards 1/27/82 (Sides 1 & 2) (Box 1)
      Continued from Tape #55; Early Firestone days/Experiences with gangsters in the East.
    - JDN with the Hallwards 1/29/82 (Side 1) (Box 1)
      Talks about Dr. & Mdme. Carrel/The war years and their deaths.
    - Library of Congress Luncheon, May 1977, Honoring Charles Lindbergh (Sides 1 & 2) (Box 1)
    - JDN, Ernie Vandeweghe, Denise Wood, Ellie discuss the book—Feb. 1982, California (Side B) (Box 1)
    - JDN, Ellie, Lee Roddy discuss the book—also Garrett Stearly (Brake lining story, Edison's brightest boys), Feb. 1982, California (Sides 1 & 2) (Box 1)
    - JDN, Ellie, Lee Roddy discuss book, Feb. 1982, California (Sides 1 & 2) (Box 1)
    - Lindbergh Fund Raising Dinner, Chicago, 1977; Land Lindbergh & Lowell Thomas, etc. (Sides 1 & 2) (Box 1)
    - JDN talks April 1982 (Side B) (Box 1)
      The TNT Story/Army days/Illeac w/ Charles & Carrell/MRA Denmark trip.
    - Death of Mr. Edison JDN, April 1982 (Side 2) (Box 1)
    - JDN talks to Reeve, Lee Roddy (Side A) (Box 1)
      Re: Book, also memories of Thos. Edison.
    - JDN letter to Lee Roddy, May 1982 (Sides A & B) (Box 1)
      Re: the book/Mary Geddes, Ellie and JDN talk of early Phila. days/MA & DOC/Family stories/JDN as a little boy, etc.
    - JDN, the Firestone years/Meeting Mr. Ford/Mr. Firestone/Leaving Firestone (Side 1) (Box 1)
    - Excerpts from speeches made at Lindbergh Dinner 5/22/82 (St. Louis); Reeve, Cliff Robertson, Dr. Maccready, etc. (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous notes from Lee Roddy (Sides 1 & 2; Lee Roddy Tape 1) (Box 1)
      Re: JDN book 5/25/82, FMB.
    - Notes from Lee Roddy on JDN book 5/25/82, Fort Myers Beach ((Sides 1 & 2; Lee Roddy Tape 2) (Box 1)
    - Lee Roddy—first rough draft of chapter I opening with death of Edison. 5/29/82 FMB. (Side 1 only; Lee Roddy Tape 3) (Box 1)
    - Lee Roddy for JDN book, May 27 1982 (Fort Myers Beach) (Sides A & B; Lee Roddy Tape 4) (Box 1)
      Works on Hallward chapter XV, etc.
    - Lee Roddy—notes on JDN book Hallward chapter XVI, etc., May 1982, FMB (Side B Only; Lee Roddy Tape 5). (Box 1)
    - JDN notes on book, May 29, 1982 (Side A only) (Box 1)
      Letter to Lee Roddy (FMB)/June 9th Silver Lake/JDN talks of Boy Scout days in Penna/His discussion with AML Re: book.
    - Lee Roddy on JDN thoughts 5/29/82 (Newton home, FMB); Re: book (Side A opnly; Lee Roddy Tape 6) (Box 1)
    - Lee Roddy—notes on book (One page only; Lee Roddy Tape 7) (Box 1)
    - JDN notes from the "Purple File" (Sides 1 & 2) (Box 1)
      Re: The book, points #l thru #130.
    - JDN notes from "Purple File" (Side 1; 79, 83) (Box 1)
      Re: The book, points #131-#150.
    - JDN, Ellie, Lee & Cicely Roddy (Side 2 only) (Box 2)
      JDN, Ellie, Lee & Cicely Roddy talk about the book and JDN tells the Sharkey-Dempsey fight story
    - Lee & Cicely Roddy, w/ JDN & Ellie, July 1982 (FMB) (Sides 1 & 2; Lee Roddy Tape 8) (Box 2)
      Discuss death of Mr. Edison/His philosophy/Mr. Firestone's opinion of Mr. Edison's beliefs in the hereafter, and Lee Roddy makes notes from articles, re: Edison Park/Edison experiments/Quotes by Ford/Dr. Carrel/Experiments/ Hearing aid story/Humidifier from Collier.
    - Lee & Cicely Roddy, w/ JDN & Ellie, July 1982 (Sides 1 & 2; Lee Roddy Tape 9) (Box 2)
      Dudley's letter to Newtons/Death of Edison/Meeting Edison/Meeting Mr. Firestone/Meeting Ford/Meeting Mrs. Edison/Hearing aid story/Going to Venice with Mrs. Edison/ Square dancing with Fords/All five men giving opportunity to youth/Starting at Firestone/What we talked about w/ Carrel, Lindbergh, etc./Philosophy/The human potential.
    - JDN—notes from the "Purple File"—points #151-#208 (Side 1) (Box 2)
    - Lee Roddy reads notes on material from Carrel, Lindbergh (Sides 1 & 2; Lee Roddy Tape 10) (Box 2)
      JDN talks about Conrad Hunte, Jack Hogan, Walter Lambert, Phyllis Konstam, Frank Buchman. JDN talks about Firestone/JDN & Bud going to Spain/Lindbergh going to Germany/Letter from AML on Marriage/Death of Lindbergh/Visit to him in hospital/His flight to Maui/JDN giving up alcohol and cigarettes/Bud Firestone.
    - JDN, Ellie, Lee & Cicely Roddy (Sides 1 & 2; Lee Roddy Tape 11) (Box 2)
      MRA days/Sam Shoemaker in China/Airlines strike/Ellie's meeting Sam Shoemaker/MA & fishing pier story/MRA Caribbean days/Mackinac Island/George West in Burma.
    - Ellie's birthday party, May 1982; Ellie talks about early days in New York working at NYU/First meeting JDN at MRA house parties/Ellie goes west with Mrs. Edison/Visiting Hollywood with Mrs. Edison/Mary Geddes & JDN talk of early days in Fort Myers/Ford plays golf/Ford talks to truck driver outside Ford home/Edison searches for Rubber/Goldenrod/Going to movies w/ Edison (Box 2)
    - TV program on Ford/His early days/Peace ship/His philosophy/"The Dearborn" (Box 2)
    - JDN talks to Stanley & Jeneane Moss in Hendersonville, N.C., Sept. 1982; Re: the book, the format, general contents, titles, reasons for writing book, etc. (Box 2)
    - Conversation re: the book between JDN/Reeve/Marie/Barbara, 4/26/83 (FMB) (Side B) (Box 2)
    - Conversation re: the book between JDN/EFN/the Hallwards/Reeve/AML, April 1983 (Newton Home) (Box 2)
    - JDN/Hallwards, July 1983; JDN answers questions per Marie's letter of 7/8/83 (Side 1) (Box 2)
    - John Hallward dictates the Introduction (Side 2) (Box 2)
    - JDN/Hallwards, July 1983; JDN talks about his relationship with Firestone (Side 1) (Box 2)
    - JDN/Hallwards, July 1983; JDN answers questions on Firestone to Marie's letter of 7/8/83 (Side 2) (Box 2)
    - JDN/Hallwards, July 1983; JDN answers questions on Firestone to Marie's letter of 7/8/83 Continued (Side 1) (Box 2)
    - JDN/Barbara—the Carrels, August 1983 (Sides 1 & 2) (Box 2)
    - JDN/Barbara—philosophy of Carrel/CAL/JDN, Aug. 1983 (Sides 1 & 2) (Box 2)
    - JDN—speaks at opening of Sanibel Open House, 12/83, with Ellie—speak of early days at FMB (Sides 1 & 2) (Box 2)
    - Reeve Lindbergh/1984—First chapter/Edison (Box 2)
    - Reeve Lindbergh/1984—Chapters II & III/Firestone (Box 2)
  - Charles A. Lindbergh material in files
    - Newspaper Clippings & Articles:
      - CAL Flight N.Y.-Paris (Box 2)
      - 1930s, 1930-1939 (Box 2)
      - Pre-War World War II (Box 2)
      - 1945-1949 (Box 2)
      - 1950s (Box 2)
      - 1960s (Box 2)
      - 1970s (Box 2)
      - 50th anniversary of flight (Box 3)
      - Death & burial of CAL (Box 3)
      - 1974 to present (Box 3)
      - Fort Myers beach/captiva (Box 3)
      - Heritage week—1985 (Box 3)
      - 60th anniversary of flight—1987 (Box 3)
      - Epcot symposium—1989 (Box 3)
      - Articles written by CAL
        - Addresses by CAL
          - May 3, 1941, St. Louis Arena (Box 3)
          - June 20, 1941, Hollywood Bowl (Box 3)
          - July 1, 1941 San Francisco (Box 3)
        - Letter to Americans (America First Letter) (Box 3)
        - "The Wisdom of Wilderness" (Life Magazine) (Box 3)
        - Address at Georgetown (Carrel Centennial Conference) (Box 3)
        - Forwards by CAL
          - "Carrying the Fire" (Box 3)
          - "Visionary Surgeon" (Box 3)
          - "The Gentle Tasaday" (Box 3)
      - Articles written about CAL & Dr. Carrel
        - "More Will Live"—Saturday Evening Post 7/23/38 (Box 3)
      - Copies of autographs of books signed by CAL (Box 3)
      - Letters from CAL (Box 3)
      - Letters to CAL (Box 3)
      - Letters to/from CAL to others than J.D.N. (Box 3)
      - Aeronautical Chamber of Commerce of America, Inc., banquet in honor of CAL, 1927 June 16 (Box 3)
      - Charles A. Lindbergh Fund material in file
        - 1978 Princess Grace benefit (Box 8)
        - 1979 awards dinner (Box 8)
        - 1980 awards dinner (Box 8)
        - 1981 awards dinner (Box 8)
        - 1982 Awards Nominations Committee-awards dinner/four million dollar fund drive (Box 8)
        - 1983 awards dinner (Box 8)
        - 1984 awards dinner (Box 8)
        - 1985 awards dinner (Box 8)
        - 1986 awards dinner (Box 8)
        - Symposium at Epcot, 1986 (Box 8)
        - 60th Anniversary (Box 9)
        - 1987 awards dinner (Box 9)
        - 60th anniversary of flight, 1987 (Box 9)
        - 1988 awards dinner (Box 9)
        - 1989 awards dinner (Box 9)
        - "A Perspective for the '90's: A World in Search of Meaning," Wm. Van Dusen Wishard (Box 9)
        - Brochures (Box 9)
        - Exhibits
          - H.R.H The Prince Philip, Duke of Edinburgh (Box 9)
          - The Honorable Clairborn Pell (Box 9)
          - Mr. Maurice F. Strong (Box 9)
        - Future events:, 1981-1982 (Box 9)
        - Lindberg lectures (Box 9)
        - Invitations:, 1980-1981 (Box 9)
        - Maui—Gravesite (Box 9)
        - Minnesota exhibition:, 1982 November (Box 9)
        - 1977 Spirit of St. Louis (Box 10)
        - Board meetings
          - 1980-1981 (Box 10)
          - 1982-1985 (Box 10)
          - 1986-1987 (Box 10)
        - Lindbergh Spirit of St. Louis postage stamps (Box 10)
        - Articles: Newspaper clippings and Magazine (Box 10)
        - Materials received under separate cover (Box 11)
  - Charles A. Lindbergh & family material in files
    - Articles about Anne Lindbergh (Box 4)
    - Articles by Anne Lindbergh (Box 4)
    - Copies of autographs of books signed by AML (Box 4)
    - Letters to Anne Lindbergh (Box 4)
    - Letters from Anne Lindbergh (Box 4)
    - A.M.L. letters to others (not J.D.N.) (Box 4)
    - Articles about Jon Lindbergh, Land Lindbergh, Reeve Lindbergh, Ansy Lindbergh, Scott Lindbergh (Box 4)
    - Letters to/from Jon Lindbergh, Land Lindbergh, Reeve Lindbergh, Ansy Lindbergh, Scott Lindbergh (Box 4)
    - Maui (CAL grave) articles & letters (Box 4)
    - Berlin alert articles & letters (Box 4)
    - Lindbergh pamphlets (Box 4)
    - The Alternative Magazine (Box 4)
    - Copy Wartime Journals (Box 4)
    - Miscellaneous on Uncommon Friends:
      - Backup (Box 4)
      - Transcripts (Box 4)
      - Articles indirectly concerning CAL (Box 5)
      - AML insertations and changes (Box 5)
  - Henry Ford material in file
    - Statements and quotes by Henry Ford & article "Thinking Out Loud" by Henry Ford (Box 5)
    - Items received (Box 11)
    - Newspaper clippings & articles on Henry Ford (Box 5)
    - Letters to and from Mrs. Clara Ford (Box 5)
    - Letters to and from Frank Campsall (Box 5)
    - Articles about Henry Ford ( Reader's Digest magazine)
      - "Henry Ford talks to young men" (Box 5)
      - "And then came Ford" (Box 5)
      - "Mr. Ford doesn't care" (Box 5)
    - Pamphlets about Henry Ford (Box 5)
    - Possible "Uncommon Friends" book material (second draft) (Box 5)
    - Copies of autographed pages of books from Ford/family (Box 5)
    - Lowell Thomas remembers Henry Ford (Box 5)
    - March 1, 1971 (Box 5)
    - May 21, 1979 (Box 5)
    - February 16, 1981 (plus others) (Box 5)
  - Thomas A. Edison material in files
    - Telegrams (Box 11)
    - Letters to James D. Newton (Box 11)
    - Articles from Newsweek, High Fidelity magazine, American Legion magazine, The Smithsonian magazine, etc. (Box 11)
    - Additional folder re: Edison (Box 11)
    - Newspaper articles:
      - 1920s (Box 5)
      - 1930s (Box 5)
      - 1940s (Box 5)
      - 1960s (Box 5)
      - 1970s (Box 5)
      - 1980s to present (Box 5)
      - Centennial (Box 5)
      - Death & burial (?) (Box 5)